Kseniia Zaitseva

+381629378980 · resong@icloud.com · github.com/iamresong Novi Sad, Serbia

DATA ANALYST

Data Analyst with 1 year of experience in analyzing large data sets and data visualization in retail and wholesale to have business insights and making reports. I have experience in marketing analytics, using tools such as SQL, Python, Excel and Tableau. Expertise in analyzing customer behavior, sales trends, market dynamics, and supply chain performance. I know how to transform numbers into valuable insights.

SKILLS

SQL Excel Tableau Data Analytics Data Visualization Marketing Analytics

Python, used libraries: NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

HMAX Beograd Data Analyst

Feb 2023 - Present

- · Wholesale analysis, identification of popular products, profitable product categories
- Customer analysis to understand preferences, buying behavior, and segmentation, enabling the development of targeted marketing strategies
- Inventory and supply analysis: optimizing inventory and supply management, forecasting demand, determining optimal inventory levels, and improving supply and logistics processes
- Pricing strategy analysis, optimizing pricing policies, explores competitive prices, and analyzes the impact of price changes on sales volume and profit
- · Forecasting demand, production optimization, inventory, and supply chain management

MadWave Europe Data Analyst

May 2022 - Oct 2022

- · Exporting and cleaning data as well as maintaining large data sets
- Retail analytics with using big data to optimize pricing, supply chain movement, and improve customer loyalty
- Gathering and analyzing data related to the performance of retail stores
- Creating reports and visualizations to summarize findings and provide recommendations on how to improve store operations or increase sales
- Reviewing financial records, interviewing employees, observing customer behavior, and performing other tasks that help gain an understanding of how well individual stores are performing
- Analyzing data such as revenue growth rates, inventory turnover rates, and profit margins, interpreting data and providing ongoing reports on a weekly and monthly basis

NOVATEK Aug 2020 - Apr 2022

Civil Engineer

- Documentary support for the implementation of an investment and construction project at all stages of its life cycle, as well as the organization of construction production
- · Drawing up as-built documentation
- · Making acts and drawings
- · Calculation of estimates

EDUCATION

Novosibirsk State University of Architecture and Construction (SIBSTRIN)
Bachelor of Civil Engineering

2015 - 2020